JULY 22 (FIFTH LOOP)
（7月22日，第五輪）
Ushio?
潮？
Hizuru!
日鶴姐姐！
Thank goodness, you're alive again!
太好了，日鶴姐姐復活了！
Wait, Nezu! Let me explain!
等一下，根津先生，聽我說…
Kofune's daughter died yesterday! You're with the shadows after all!
這不就是昨天死去的 小舟家的女兒嗎？
Stop, Nezu. Don't rush to judgment.
住手，根津，別急
I died?
我死了嗎？
Yes.
是的
I see.
原來如此
The world you observe becomes reality. Four-Arm said that.
你觀測到的世界會變為現實 四手是這麼說的吧？
Yes. But why do I have that power?
對，但是為什麼 我會擁有那樣的力量？
If your right eye belonged to Heine…
如果你的右眼原本是海涅的東西
that eye is made of shadows.
那麼那隻眼睛就是影子變的
You don't remember when it was printed?
你不記得是什麼時候被印製的吧？
I'm not sure, but probably after I came back to the island.
我沒注意到是什麼時候…
The one who gave that eye to Shinpei was you, Ushioh.
把那隻眼睛給予網代慎平的人 就是你，潮
Me?
我嗎？
How?
這是怎麼回事？
Why do you think you failed the last loop?
你認為上一輪失敗的原因是什麼？
One was acting separately from you after defeating Mio's shadow.
其中一個原因是打倒泠的影子後 和老師你們分開行動
This time, we need to work together.
如果可以的話 希望這次大家可以同心協力
Hey…
什…
I agree.
我同意
Hey, Hizuru.
喂，日鶴！
T-That was…
這傢伙…
Nezu, Ushioh is an ally. She was our ally till the end.
根津，潮是站在我們這邊的
Ms. Nagumo. Can you hear me?
南雲老師，聽得到嗎？
That's why we have that message and Shinpei's right eye here.
我才會收到那條訊息
I trust you.
我相信你
Ms. Nagumo.
老師
It's human nature to believe in fiction. Let it be riches, religion, or stories.
能夠從心底相信虛構是人的天性
That's why I'm a novelist.
所以我才會是小說家
I'm not fictional.
我才不是虛構的
I know.
我知道啦
That's the first time I saw her smile.
第一次看到老師的笑容
Jeez… So you're risking your lives too?
你們也是在以命相搏嗎？
Is Four-Arm trying to revive Heine?
四手的目的是讓海涅復活嗎？
It fed a lot of people to Heine at the summer festival.
在夏日慶典上 四手讓海涅吃了大量的人
What happens after that ceremony?
雖然不清楚在儀式之後 會發生什麼事情
Something about an "Ending…"
但我記得他說了一句“結局”…
That massive body is Hiruko's true form.
那個巨大的影子 就是那傢伙的本體，蛭子神
The shadow at Shiori's feet is just part of that.
如果詩織腳下的影子 不過是那影子的一部分
That explains why we couldn't kill Shiori no matter what.
那就能解釋 怎麼殺她都殺不死的原因了
But Shiori isn't strong in battle. She walks, and that's it.
但是影子詩織的戰鬥能力不高 只能做到行走的程度
Hiruko is too weak to leave the cave.
蛭子神很虛弱，無法離開那個洞窟
Could this be it?
所以是這樣嗎？
-HEINE IS IMMOBILE (WEAK LEGS) -TRUE FORM (HIRUKO) IS WEAK AND IMMOBILE
（海涅狀態無法行動，下肢不便 本體蛭子神也衰弱，無法動彈）
-SHIORI IS MOBILE -FOOT SHADOW IS PART OF TRUE FORM
（詩織狀態可走動，腳下影子 是本體的一部分，正在參加葬禮）
What is your plan?
你們的計劃是什麼？
I'd like to go underground now and defeat the true form…
雖然很想馬上潛入地下，擊潰本體
but if we can't defeat Four-Arm, it'll end up like the last loop.
若我們沒有能確實打倒四手的對策 可能會重蹈覆轍
Moreover, I'm worried about Mio. I need a plan about Sou too.
而且我很擔心泠還有窗他們
I want us to capture Shiori at Koba Mart like last time.
我認為應該和上一輪一樣 到小早超商抓住影子詩織
You can't kill her, though. What's the point of capturing her?
但她不是殺不死嗎？ 抓到又能怎麼樣？
Right, but I might be able to erase her.
關於這方面，我也許可以將她消除
FRIEND
（第13集，朋友）
Yeah, I feel better than I did yesterday.
嗯，比昨天好多了
It's because Shinpei's back.
因為小慎回來了
I see.
是嗎？
Oh, what's wrong, Sou?
怎麼了嗎？窗
I need to talk to Father about Ushio.
我有事找老爸，是關於潮的事
Leave. I don't have time for that.
出去，我沒時間
Seido.
阿青
Don't worry about him.
你不用管
Make some time for him, will you?
沒時間就創造時間，好嗎？
Negoro. Take care of the rest.
根來，接下來的事拜託你了
Father!
老爸！
Come to my room tonight at 10. I'll spare five minutes.
今晚10點來我房間 給你五分鐘的時間
Thanks, Mother.
謝謝你，媽媽
Sure, but what is it about?
沒事，你想和你爸說什麼？
Nothing much.
也沒什麼，一點小事
Yes. Shinpei Ajiro is looking into the shadow sickness.
對，網代慎平在調查影子病的事
What's going on? It was Ushio Kofune, now it's Hizuru Minakata.
到底是怎麼回事？
Why are people sniffing around now?
為什麼會出現這麼多 調查這件事的人？
It's unlikely a coincidence that Hizuru Minakata returned.
南方日鶴回島上應該不是偶然
Ushio must have contacted Shinpei.
而慎平那邊應該是小潮曾聯繫過他
Is it true that Ushio's shadow wasn't erased and is now missing?
你們沒能把影子潮徹底消除 還讓她跑了，這是真的嗎？
Don't worry. We'll find and erase it. First, we'll get to her family.
放心吧，我一定會找到她 將她消除，先從她的家人入手
Turn the entire Kofune family into shadows?
把小舟一家全都變成影子？
That's the plan. Including Shinpei Ajiro.
就是這麼打算的，包括網代慎平在內
Well? What is it? Yes, I'll be there.
怎麼了？好，我馬上去
Hello? My mother needs me. I must go.
喂？不好意思 母親在叫我，我先掛了
Mama's boy.
媽寶男
Today, we have a report from Kinokawa City.
今天轉播的地方是紀之川市
Wakayama's seasonal treats are delicious…
這個季節的和歌山特產 將為各位帶來關於美食的話題…
KOBA MART YOMOGIMOCHI
（艾草麻糬）
You're up, Ryunosuke.
該你出場了，龍之介
Erase Shiori?
也許可以消除？消除影子詩織嗎？
In the last loop, I felt Heine coming in and trying to mess with my head.
剛才我差點被海涅操控大腦 她進入了我體內
So maybe I can reverse that route.
所以如果我順著路徑反向追蹤…
Can you do the same?
你是說，你也能做到同樣的事嗎？
I don't get it, but it seems like it's worth trying.
雖然聽不懂你們在說什麼 但看來很值得一試
Yes. I would like to put it down myself, though.
對，雖然我很想親手葬送她
Nezu told me last time.
上一輪我聽根津先生說過
Ryunosuke was killed by a shadow 14 years ago…
14年前龍之介先生被影子殺害
and there were ligature marks on his neck.
遺體的脖子上有勒痕
Did Heine kill Ryunosuke?
殺害龍之介先生的就是海涅吧
Yes. And she was my friend.
對，而且那孩子曾經是我的朋友
-What… -Your friend?
-什麼？ -朋友？
Pick it up. We can talk more later.
接吧，具體的事之後再說
I wanna hear Mio's voice! Should I pick it up?
我想聽泠的聲音，我來接吧！
Dummy!
你是笨蛋嗎？
I was just joking.
開個玩笑而已
She's alive. The phone is vibrating to tell me she's alive.
還活著，手機的震動證明了泠還活著
-I won't let Mio die again. -Hello? Sorry.
我不會讓泠再次死去
Repeating the previous actions should yield the same result.
只要重複上次的行動 應該就能得到同樣的結果
So Plan B is to capture Heine.
也就是說，用B計劃能抓住海涅
Heine is the one who took you and Asako from me.
海涅是把你還有朝子 從我身邊奪走的罪魁禍首
If it weren't for Heine, Ushio Kofune and the others would still be alive.
只要沒有海涅，小舟潮就不會死 誰都不會死
Let's end this, Ryunosuke.
結束這一切吧，龍之介
Roger that, Sis.
明白，姐姐
Are you ready?
準備好了嗎？
I've been ready before you were even born.
早在你出生前，我就準備好了
I'm good to go.
我隨時都可以出動
Erase Heine, whom Four-Arm treasures. Here and now.
要除掉海涅
Then we'll save everyone from the end of that summer festival.
如此一來就能把大家 從夏日慶典的慘劇中拯救出來
Hi! Hizuru!
是日鶴啊！
Hey, did I catch you at dinner… Excuse me, I had some gifts.
晚餐時間來打擾，真是對不…
Come in.
進來坐坐吧
Thank you.
那就打擾了
No one is looking. You can come out, Ushioh.
已經沒人了
You transform, you fight. You're like Pretty Cure.
又能變身又能戰鬥 你好像光之美少女
What? Really? That was my dream in kindergarten!
真的嗎？天啊 我實現幼兒園時的夢想了！
You know Pretty Cure?
你知道光之美少女嗎？
My granddaughter used to like it.
我孫子以前很喜歡
I realized something amazing!
我發現了一件很厲害的事
The nail gun that Four-Arm destroyed?
這是被四手破壞的釘槍嗎？
you can bring the data you scanned the last time to the next loop!
能將上一輪掃描的數據 帶到下一個輪迴嗎？
Isn't it great?
很厲害吧？
Yes! You're amazing, Ushioh! Was that outfit scanned last time too?
對，很厲害，你太厲害了，潮
It's too bad, though. I wish this wasn't damaged.
不過好可惜 要是這個沒被我弄壞就好了
It should be fine…
沒關係
since I have the original.
原型我帶著
Nezu brought two guns: his Nail Gun A and my Nail Gun B.
根津先生帶來兩把釘槍 他的是釘槍A，我的是釘槍B
Ushioh scans the data from Nail Gun B.
潮重新掃描釘槍B
She overwrites the old data, then destroys the original.
覆蓋了舊的數據，然後消除原型
I see.
原來如此
Now I can use Nail Gun B again.
這樣B又能使用了
We'll put copying Nail Gun A on hold, because Ushioh's storage is full.
本來也想複製釘槍A 但潮的存儲空間滿了，暫時不複製
It's been five minutes since Ryunosuke went in.
龍之介進入房間已經過五分鐘了
It's about time he tells us to switch to Plan B.
差不多該聯繫我們變更B計劃了吧
Yes. Then two minutes later, Shiori comes down from the balcony.
是的，在龍之介先生 聯繫我們的兩分鐘後
The third shot misses and she flees…
第三根釘子會射偏，讓影子詩織逃掉
but I capture her by the green tea ice cream banner.
而我會在綠色冰淇淋 旗幟那邊抓住她…
Finally, I'll erase her.
最後由我來消除她
Yes.
好
First, we wait to hear from Ryunosuke.
先等龍之介先生聯繫
What the…
什…
Run… away.
快逃
-Ms. Nagumo… -Wait.
-南雲老師！ -等一下！
This is no longer like the previous July 22…
這裡已經和之前的22日不一樣…
I see you are all together.
你們好啊，都到齊了
Hi-Hizuru!
日鶴！
It can't be. Why? Why are you here?
這不可能，為什麼你會在這裡？
You don't play fair, Shinpei.
耍賴是不對的哦，慎平
What?
什麼？
Didn't I tell you that time?
那個時候我不是說了嗎？
I told you, "I found you."
“找到你了”
That is a mark. I can find you in any world you go to.
這是印記，之後不管你去哪個世界 我都能馬上找到你
Get it? I've been following you.
明白了嗎？我一直跟著你
Didn't our eyes meet at the end of that summer festival?
我們的視線對上了吧？ 在那個夏日慶典的最後
I can loop too.
我也可以輪迴
I knew you'd come here because I read Ryunosuke's memory last time.
我在上次讀取龍之介的記憶時 就知道你們今天會來這裡了
It… can't be…
怎麼會這樣？
We don't need two observers.
不需要兩個觀測者
It's either Mother…
母親…
or you.
或是你
The one who survives will decide which world is real!
只有最後活下來的人 所看到的世界才是現實！
Come on! I'll kill you!
來啊，看我殺了你！
Three shots… What?
三發…什麼？
The three shots didn't stop him?
三根釘子縫影子竟然無效？
No!
不行
If I scan everything, I'll disappear. But I'll take that one arm!
全部掃描的話，我就會消失 但是一條手臂的話…
Whatever.
算了
This is just a greeting, Shinpei Ajiro.
算是和你打個招呼，網代慎平
Loop as many times as you like.
不管你重複多少次都無所謂
I'll find you every time…
每一次我都會找到你
and seal that power in the end.
最終將你的力量封印！
I was careless. I should have known that the enemy may have the same powers.
海涅，是我太天真了，我早該料到 敵人也擁有同樣的力量！
Heine came from the summer festival. Those two died because I was careless.
那傢伙也是從夏日慶典來的
Ushioh! Where is she?
潮，潮呢？
Right here!
-我在這裡！ -什麼？
Sorry. Did your neck hurt? I tried to make it as quick as possible.
抱歉，脖子很痛吧？
Thank goodness, Ushioh. I'm fine. You did great.
太好了，潮，我沒事，你做得很好
What about you? Are you okay?
對了，你的自我呢？沒事吧？
I thought I could figure out who Four-Arm was…
我是想說要是能知道四手是誰就好了
but it was empty.
結果發現他是個空殼
It has no data in it. How is it even moving?
那傢伙的身體沒有數據 到底是怎麼動起來的？
I see…
是嗎？
But it smells similar to Heine.
可是那傢伙是怎麼回事？ 散發著和海涅一樣的氣味
Can we win against an enemy who can loop?
你覺得能贏嗎？敵人也能輪迴
Heine is most likely just using your power to loop.
也許海涅只是利用你的力量才能輪迴
So she'll loop to the same place as us. Our conditions are even.
所以下次的起點應該和我們一樣 條件是平等的
We can win, I know we can!
是我們的話就能贏的
Thanks.
謝謝
BISTRO KOFUNE
（小舟西餐廳）
What the…
奇怪
This is our house.
這裡是我們家啊
Even if the start point changed, when were we here?
就算輪迴的起點發生了偏移… 我們來過這裡嗎？
This is odd. It shouldn't be raining. July 22 was sunny.
不對，好奇怪，不應該有雨的 22日一直是晴天啊
Hey, hold on. Wait up, Sis.
等一下，等一下啦，姐姐
That is…
剛才那是…
No way. Ms. Nagumo?
難道是南雲老師？
No point thinking. Let's follow them, Shinpei!
想再多也沒用，慎平，追上他們兩個
Right.
好
Huh? It looks busy today.
怎麼會這樣？今天好多人
Those two are Hizuru and her twin Ryunosuke.
這兩個人果然是日鶴小姐 和她的雙胞胎弟弟，龍之介先生
What is the meaning of this?
怎麼回事？
When I died the first time, something similar happened.
第一次死的時候發生過類似的事
Welcome. For two?
歡迎光臨，兩位嗎？
Ah. Why are you wearing an apron, Akemi?
你怎麼穿著圍裙啊？曉見阿姨
It's Bistro Kofune's 10th anniversary…
今天是小舟西餐廳 開店十周年的紀念日
so everyone came by to eat here today.
島上的大家都來吃飯了
Is that right? Congrats!
原來是這樣，恭喜
Thanks. So I'm helping too.
謝謝，所以我也來幫忙了
Mother?
媽媽？
It's really Akemi. Wow!
真的，是曉見阿姨啊，不得了！
So this is the past.
這裡果然是過去
It's 14 years ago.
14年前
When I died the first time, I was with Mio and the same happened.
我第一次死的時候，泠在我身邊 當時也發生了這樣的情況
I was at the beach where you died. It was the past, and I saw everything.
我在你死去的私人沙灘上 親眼看到過去發生的事
That must've been Mio's memory. Then is this Ms. Nagumo's memory?
那是泠的記憶嗎？ 那這裡就是南雲老師的記憶？
Dessert is on us today!
今天免費贈送甜品哦
Awesome!
太好了！
I don't like crowds, so I'm going home.
人太多了很不舒服，我要回去了
Hey, wait a sec!
等一下！
Asako. You were here?
朝子，你在啊？
It's a special day for Kofune. We have to celebrate together.
今天是小舟家喜慶的日子 大家一起慶祝吧
I don't feel the need to make a fuss to celebrate.
我不認為慶祝 就必須一大堆人吵吵鬧鬧的
You don't need to go home, either! Don't you have a heart?
你都來了也沒必要回去吧 你的心到底是不是肉長的啊？
I am human, so I have a heart. But I want to leave.
我是人類，心當然是肉長的 但是我想回去…
Ms. Nagumo really hasn't changed.
-南雲老師從小就是這樣啊 -又說這種歪理
Happy 10th anniversary, Bistro Kofune!
恭喜小舟西餐廳開業十周年！
You should leave.
你回去
Oh, Hizuru. You look so happy to see me. I'm flattered.
日鶴，看到我這麼開心嗎？ 真是讓人不好意思
Those ten years went quick.
十年還真是一眨眼就過了啊
Alain, your food is always great. Please don't change.
亞倫，那個，你做的菜一直都很好吃
Hey, did you look in the mirror?
真是的，你出門照鏡子了嗎？
You haven't shaved! Your hair is messy too.
鬍子，頭髮也亂了
Oh, sorry. I forgot.
抱歉，我忘了
Your dad came too. This must've been quite a day.
連你爸爸也來了 當年還有這樣的一天啊
Yeah, it's amazing. They're moving.
是啊，真不得了，他們都活著
Their voices. Gestures. That's how they were.
他們兩個的聲音、舉止 原來是那樣的啊
What jobs did your parents do?
慎平的爸媽是做什麼工作來著？
They were nautical archeologists. They dive underwater.
水下考古學家，要潛入水下工作
Masahito, so you're finally a priest.
真砂人終於當上宮司了啊
Yes. I have a lot to learn, but I am doing my best.
是啊，很多事都是第一次接觸 不過我在努力了
What's new, Toru?
透，你最近怎麼樣？
I'm thinking about diving to that point I mentioned before.
之前提過的那個地點 我想潛下去看看
Hitogashima Island has so much unique history. I'm glad I moved here.
日都島是一座很有歷史的島 非常有意思
Food is great here too.
食物也很美味
Hey, Ryunosuke. Why is Hizuru in a bad mood?
喂，龍，日鶴好像心情很差？
Well, it's actually my fault.
對，其實是我惹她不高興的
I never should have told you.
早知道就不告訴你了
Huh? What is it?
什麼？
She says she made a friend.
還不是姐姐說她交到朋友了
Unbelievable, right? So I told her she's dreaming.
難以置信吧？ 所以我才問說她是不是在做夢
I told her it was an imaginary friend, and she got mad.
是不是只有她才能看到的那種朋友 然後她就生氣了
That's just cruel, Ryunosuke.
龍你也太…的確難以置信
I'm joking. Sorry Hizuru, I believe you.
-喂 -開玩笑的，抱歉，日鶴，我相信你
You're joking? I don't need a joker to believe me.
所以是騙我？得到一個騙子的信任 我可一點都不開心
Asako didn't mean it like that.
小朝不是那個意思啦…
It's fine, Ryunosuke.
沒關係啦，龍
Tell me about your friend.
所以是什麼樣的人啊？
We have less than 20 kids at school. Where did you meet someone new?
整個學校的國中生不到20人 是在哪裡認識的新朋友？
Mt. Takanosu.
鷹之巢山
The setting changed again.
場景又變了
HISHIGATA CLINIC
（菱形醫院）
Shinpei. This place…
慎平，這裡是…
Yes. The old Hishigata Clinic.
對，是舊菱形醫院
Was she really here?
真的是在這種地方見到的嗎？
Is she from the island?
是誰家的孩子？島上的嗎？
I think so.
應該是吧
"You think so"?
應該？
She's probably not from our time.
而且她恐怕不是這個時代的人
You'll get it once you see her. She usually appears around now.
你們見到後就知道了 她總是在這個時間出現
There.
那裡
The light on the second floor will turn on.
二樓的窗戶那裡會亮燈
It's gotta be a ghost.
那是幽靈吧
This is too creepy. I hear there are ghosts here.
等等，太嚇人了 這裡有傳聞說會鬧鬼
I don't see anyone.
沒出現
Maybe she won't come today.
今天也許不會來吧
Hizuru, we should head back. Our parents will be worried.
日鶴，該回去了，父母會擔心
It'll be dangerous to go back once it gets dark.
天黑再回去就危險了
I promised to meet her today. I keep promises.
我跟她約好了今天見面 我要遵守諾言
Hizuru!
日鶴！
I'll take you home, Asako. Sis gets stubborn like that.
我先送你回家吧，小朝
It can't be.
不會吧
Good evening…
晚安
Heine.
海涅